So this is Zainab. She's a
really big supporter of mine who I have
had the pleasure of talking to in my
Discord server so many times. She asked
just incredible questions and I thought
how cool would it be to do an interview
with a fan because who knows the music
better and who has more contacts than a
fan. A lot of times journalists ask me
questions and I'm like you have not
listened to the music, you know.
So everyone give it up for Zainab one
time. Thank
you so much. Thank you for having me. Of
course. It's going to take like 5
minutes for my anxiety to to like calm
down. So bear with me.
Okay, please. I I appreciate that. So
definitely want to start off by saying
thank you to Russ for A like inviting me
here and just giving me the opportunity
to do this.
I was scrolling through Discord and I
found like I think my first mentioning
of wanting to do an interview was like
2022 or 2023. So like this is my own
kind of manifestation coming to life. So
I have I have like screenshots of that.
So like the fact that this is actually
happening and that I'm here talking to
you is like my little dream come true.
So thank you so much and your team for
everyone to like make this happen. Yes.
So I want to start off by saying like
again I've been a fan for a really long
time and I have a lot of like respect
and admiration for you and your craft
and
especially the community that you
fostered like not just through Discord
but like all social media platforms, all
that kind of stuff. You
have given us like your fans a space to
not only connect with you but like
connect within. I know for me myself
I've made so many friendships that like
I know will last a lifetime from people
from all over the world like genuinely.
So that wouldn't have happened if not
for you.
And I think I speak for a lot of people
here when I say that like I became a fan
of you and I I am a fan of you because
of your music but I stayed a fan because
of your personality, your kindness, your
authenticity and like that's what keeps
me coming to shows, that's what keeps me
like going to your like random pop up
events and stuff like that. So I just
want to start off by sincerely like
thank you so much for this opportunity.
So that's what I WANTED TO SAY.
ALL RIGHT, ANXIETY was a five now it's a
four. All right, so
I have like a vault of questions that
I've like held for years. I'm super
excited to get into it. I did want to
have a little bit of structure so I did
want to start off by talking about your
new album Wild.
So
from what you've shared so far the focus
of it is navigating the wild or unknown
of your internal world and thought
processes so that you can better engage
with your external world in a healthier
and more positive way. Yeah. So my first
question is
at what point did making this album and
kind of investigating that wild feel
like the next necessary step for you?
And to clarify what I mean by that, was
there a specific memory or turning point
or like aha moment where
you realized that there was so much more
of yourself that you don't even know
yet?
I think um
I think
that when I wanted to
go into this album process, it was just
I could have sworn I was probably about
to make another like heavy concept
album, you know, like Santiago.
Uh
and I quickly I don't know if it was an
aha moment or just sort of realizing
through numerous therapy sessions that
okay, my life is more than just the
problems that I have going on. It's
robust, it's round and I think for me, I
don't know about anyone else but it's
very difficult for me to look at my life
as this round robust experience. Like
when there's [__] up [__] going on,
I'm just like zoomed in on the problem.
And when there's good [__] going on,
unfortunately I'm not like super zoomed
in on that either because I'm still kind
of like well it's not that good because
there's some [__] up [__] going on.
You know, I don't allow myself fully to
appreciate it. So I think just early on
in the um
Well actually you know what, maybe there
was an aha moment.
On the first song I made for the album
it was a song called Embrace. And shout
out to Jake Jepson and Kiri Girls in the
back. Raise your hand guys. Man, these
two right here, I made the whole album
with these two guys. They're from
Australia. They're [__] incredible.
Make some noise for Jake Jepson and Kiri
Girls.
So
Jake, an incredible songwriter and
producer, the same with Kiri.
Found them on TikTok just scrolling.
They're [__] amazing.
Jake had this like loop up
of like him playing the guitar and
singing this like incredible melody and
I hit him and I'm like bro this shit's
[__] nuts. I want to rap on this.
I was like are you cool if we change the
hook? And I kind of
Correct me if I'm wrong but I gave you
like just the framework of like what I
wanted you to be talking about.
And what I wanted him to be talking
about on this song called Embrace was
man, instead of just resisting
life's natural unpredictability
I need to just embrace it. I spent so
much time like [__]
exhausting myself trying to like change
outcomes, control outcomes and make
things go the way I want them to go and
and then when things naturally don't go
my way sometimes it's like it's like a
gut punch. It's like I feel betrayed by
the universe. Like what the [__] Didn't
you know I was manifesting this though?
Like how could you, you know? And so
I wanted to talk about just embracing
life, embracing the unknown. And so I
gave that concept to him and he's saying
this incredible hook that's on the album
and then I just rapped for like a minute
and a half. And that was the first song
that I made after Santiago that I said
oh [__] I think I know what this next
album needs to be about.
And that was what, like October of last
year?
Yeah, so like October of last year I
made that song and I was like oh man.
I think I know what the album needs to
be about which is just embracing life's
unknown. For sure. I think that's
something that I'm sure many people have
to like come to terms with themselves as
like sitting in distress or sitting in
uncomfortability or not knowing what
what's to come in your life. I'm
like I'm sure there's other
perfectionists out there as well. Like
you don't want to do life right. You
want to do all the necessary things, do
everything that you want to do and then
if you make a mistake then it's like
[__] then like I don't know if I'm
allowed to curse.
But like then it's like all right, well
am I even worth it or am I am I a bad
person or whatever. So I feel like
sometimes it's a good reminder for us
and for a lot of other people of like
it's important to sit in that
uncomfortability because that's what it
is. That's what life is. Not everything
is going to be perfect. Not everything
is going to be
coming out and like
like manifesting the way that you want
it every single time. So I think that's
a really important lesson. Even what
you're saying like sitting in that
uncomfortability, that is something that
I resisted for so long.
And the way I avoided being
uncomfortable or dealing with it
was in the past it was drinking
going to the studio
or women. Like that was it. It was like
wait a second, that's right. I don't
have to sit in this. I don't have to
deal with this.
I can drink. I can call a chick. I can
go to the studio. Uh
and I thought that I was like somehow
being positive in that regard. Like
yeah, like I'm not letting it beat me.
You know?
But I wasn't really ever dealing with
it.
I was actually very scared to deal with
And I never thought I was one of those
people who was like oh you're scared to
be alone. Like I always looked at those
people like what's wrong with you? Like
you can't be alone? Like what do you got
going on? And
I'm that.
I didn't realize that because if I
wasn't in the studio if I wasn't you
know, with a girl and if I wasn't
drinking
I was asleep.
Do you know what I mean? I feel like a
lot I have heard my friends say this to
me because I'm a big napper. People who
sleep intentionally like it's they're
trying to waste their life away. They're
trying to like not live at that point.
You're not living because you don't want
to. Yeah, I was not down to face what I
was dealing with. Certainly not sober,
you know.
And I think this album and just this
phase of my life is me
find I mean Santiago was the start of
saying all right
let me stop moving for a second. Let me
stop trying to distract myself
whether it's women, alcohol, even the
studio.
Let me actually
inquire
to myself what like what's going on, you
know? And Santiago was the start.
And then this album
this album is me like after having done
a lot of self excavation work.
It's me sort of saying okay, I know I'm
uncomfortable.
I now know that like I'm scared of
really being seen and perceived on a
bigger level, you know.
Cuz it just makes me feel like I got to
be even more perfect and it makes me
feel like mistakes are like cannot
happen. There's too many people looking
at me now.
But I'm going to go anyway. You know,
I'm going to go after what I want
anyway, you know. And um
it's scary but I'm doing it anyway.
Yeah. And now after like starting that
process because again there's no end to
that. It's a continuous process.
What is something that you've learned
about yourself or your internal world
that maybe you didn't know before making
this album?
Um
that I was scared of more success.
Yeah.
Uh, because I, you know,
it was a scary realization because
I was worried about how my fans would
look at me.
Because
they met me
as a certain version of myself.
You know?
You guys ever date somebody and you guys
met as version 1.0 of each other? And
naturally, as you became a newer
involved version, it just didn't work
anymore.
You know? It just didn't click. Not
because like they were a piece of [__]
or whatever, but it was just oh, that
doesn't align with what I'm on anymore.
You know? You're going that way, I'm
going this way and
just is what it is. And so for me,
I'm like, damn man, I came out so
gung-ho.
I want it all. Give me it all.
And
it's because I didn't know what the cons
were. I was so focused on all the pros,
all the good stuff that's about to
happen. And I was so naive to think that
that there was never going to be
anything bad that comes with this [__]
And
now, because of like the experience, I
know that there's more [__] up [__] on
the way.
And so I'm like, damn man, I'm barely
able to handle this level of [__]
Like, maybe I don't want
more success cuz I know there's going to
be more [__]
And I'm [__] hanging on by a thread
at this [__] level. So y'all got to
go ahead. But then, my ambition
jumps in the fight and says, "What are
you doing, bro?
We didn't come this far to come this
far."
You know what I mean? Like,
life isn't over yet. It's an
never-ending process. Yeah, just like
give up.
So,
I had to just make that decision. And
it's a decision I have to make every
day, which is
I am going to go after everything I want
fulfillment-wise
regardless of the [__] that comes
with it because there's no life that you
can curate that doesn't have [__]
attached to it.
There's no life you can curate that's
going to just be like bullshit-free.
It doesn't I don't care how much money
you guys get, how much fame, how much
whatever. There's always going to be
some [__]
Always.
And I spent my whole life trying to
curate this perfect life where nothing
went wrong and,
you know? And it's just not real. And so
this album really is just like
navigating and growing up. Like that's
the phase of it. It's growing the [__]
up, which, you know, I think a lot of
people in this room maybe like did
before me, probably, you know? Like
people looking at me now like, "Dog,
what? You're 32."
What's the deal? But,
I got success at 23 years old. I made my
first million dollars at 23.
And all that did was confirm the way I
thought back then.
It
it kind of propelled me into the
suspended adolescence, in a sense.
I didn't have to grow up. My life was
sick.
You know what I mean? Like, what do you
mean? I don't got to fix my life. My
life looks awesome. And then
there is no problems. And it's really
hard to
to take inventory on your life
internally when externally everything is
going right.
And I think that
like you were mentioning Santiago before
and I wanted to ask like
um,
I wanted to point out that this is the
first album since Santiago. And I don't
know about you, but for me I'm a very
visual person. And for some reason, now
my brain categorizes your music into
pre-Santiago and post-Santiago. Wow.
Because for me it felt like a a rebirth
almost of like that was one of the more
raw and like authentic pieces of work
that you've done. Not that like other
ones haven't been. Yeah. But this I felt
like or Santiago was more confronting.
Um, so something that I wanted to ask
was, now does making music with more
self-awareness
um, make the writing process easier? Or
would you say that there is more
inspiration or incentive when you are
less introspective?
Um, to your point about Santiago, I
think Santiago was my reintroduction to
my fan base. You know? It was like
really [__] scary cuz it's like put
out self-help books and it's like here's
this dude with like this [__] heavy
therapy album. It's like, what are my
fans going to think? But, it was a
necessary reintroduction to show people
that there's more depth than just me
saying you can do it, believe in
yourselves.
You know? And
now, just being more aware and
navigating all this stuff, as far as
does it make the songwriting more
difficult? Yeah, it's more demanding
because
I want to dig deeper.
And digging deeper is tough. It's so
easy to write like surface level just
motivational
[__] like you can do it and, you know,
trust your gut and [__] like that. But,
it's tough when it's like,
okay, well, how about for the people who
don't trust themselves?
Like,
why don't they trust themselves? And
maybe where's that coming from?
You know? That's tougher to write about.
So it's harder, you're saying?
Yeah, it's harder, for sure.
Interesting. Yeah. Um, and also like
comparatively, um,
with this album you mentioned it's going
to be a lot different than Santiago,
where Santiago was in chronological
order from the beginning to end or
beginning to present, maybe. Yeah. Um,
where Wild is more of like an
amalgamation of different stories and
different uh,
parts of your life um, currently. Yeah.
Um, which style of album do you enjoy
more both as a producer and as a
listener of music?
Hm.
I think as a listener, I don't prefer
concept albums.
I just did a concept album Santiago cuz
I had to.
Like I needed to get that story off in
order for me to even be able to create
from a clear-headed place now. Um, but I
know it's like
it's not the easiest listen. Cuz you got
to listen to it in order for it to like
kind of make sense. And then even after
that, it's like,
you know, some of the stuff is heavier
messaging, you know? Um,
but from a creative perspective,
it's really fulfilling to make something
like that cuz it's like you're you're
you're creating this like puzzle and you
don't know where any of the pieces go
yet. And then all of a sudden like it
all kind of comes together.
And it just flows in this perfect way
where it's like something to really look
back on and be proud of. So making it
change your perspective on concept
albums like for It did. artists that you
listen to? It really did. It gave me a
way bigger appreciation for concept
albums because I was like, you know
what?
This is
this was really hard to make.
This was really, really intentional. And
I think now more than ever I'm trying to
be intentional with everything I do.
Santiago was so intentional.
The rollout was intentional. The
listening sessions were intentional.
Like, everything had a purpose and and
so that's really what I learned from
Santiago is to be intentional with
everything. So, with Wild, you know,
from the artwork to the album trailer,
it's like
just wanting to express myself on a
on a bigger level than just the music
and on a deeper level than just lyrics.
You know? I want everyone in here to
just [__] like
pay attention to themselves. Take
inventory of yourself. What's going on
internally? Especially the men in here
who feel like
you're not allowed to, you know? And you
got to just get over it. It's like, take
inventory. No one's saying feel sorry
for yourself and, you know, sulk around
the house and woe is me.
Like,
be resilient, but take inventory of
what's going on.
And and
try to
try to give yourself grace and try to
give yourself understanding.
Just in hopes that you can move forward
through life without so much pent-up
resentment for your [__] self.
And um, I wanted to talk about some of
the songs in Wild specifically. But
before we getting into that, I had a
question about the artwork, which is so
convenient that it's right here.
Um, so before I ask my question, um,
maybe in a few words for those that
don't know, can you explain kind of what
it what is it? What is it about? How
does it relate to Wild? So, um,
for those who don't know, like Kids
Super, one of my good friends, Colin
Tilney, he did
There's Really a Wolf album cover. He
did Zoo. He did Shake the Snow Globe.
Uh, but he's just like a very close
friend of mine and I lean on him for
like creative advice. So obviously I
went to him to get the artworks.
And he just submitted a bunch of stuff.
One of them was this. And he was like,
"I didn't do this one, but I found this.
It's [__] crazy."
He was like, "I hesitated putting it in
the deck cuz I know you're going to pick
it cuz it's minimal."
But I'm like, well, yeah. It's awesome
though and iconic. Yeah. And
so I we like linked with the artist who
like made this guy named James Coffman.
Really sick. But the reason why I picked
it and why it stood out to me,
I just love how
ambiguous it is. I love how unknown it
feels. You know? I looked at it, I
didn't quite know what animal it was.
I liked that. You know? It kind of
reminded me of
how I don't really know what
a better version of me looks like.
I don't know what an evolved version of
me looks like. And that's okay.
As long as I'm like headed in that path.
Um, I like that it was just sitting on
this white backdrop. It felt very out in
the wild, out in the open, out in the
unknown.
Um
and then really the last piece to it was
how it's looking back. Mhm.
To me that like it just embodies like
you're leaving your comfort zone, you're
going out into this blank canvas of this
white unknown space.
But like you're still looking back at
your comfort zone.
Cuz you're just not sure. And it just it
just feels like where I'm at in my life,
you know, like all right.
I'll go out here, I'll go into the
unknown of life, I'll go after what I
want, after more dreams and all that,
but like
let me just like look back one time to
make sure like
you know what I mean?
Yeah, I said that part was the thing
that I like that caught my eye the most
and like first. So I wanted to ask like
do you ever find yourself looking back
more than once or maybe looking back
more times than you would like? You
know, looking back to familiarity, to
your comfort zone, to like of course now
you're wanting to go into the wild, but
like are you truly there? Do do you ever
look back?
Um
yeah, it's like an everyday decision,
you know, to
put myself out there in
uncomfortable situations. And and you
know, what I mean by the unknown of life
is certain opportunities sometimes that
would come my way, I would just say no
to because they felt scary. It was like
social anxiety [__] You know, I've
passed on a lot of great opportunities
cuz I simply was like I'm going to be
too nervous and I'm not doing it.
You know, so even little things like
that.
You know, like there was an Apple Music
event, for example, like in LA like a
couple weeks ago and I got invited to it
and usually it's just like I'm not going
to that. Mhm. You know, cuz I'm like
there's going to be like famous people
there and I'm like I'm not dealing with
that anxiety like I'm going to stay home
and then just be like yeah, like [__]
them anyway.
You know,
um but
I was like you know what?
Let me just go. Mhm.
And I went and I was okay and it was
fine and I met a lot of cool people.
And it's like doing [__] like that that
just sort of like
makes you feel more capable
than you felt before going, you know,
cuz you're like damn, I did it.
And I was okay, you know, or like
when
I met Will Smith for the first time and
they wanted that to be on camera, they
didn't let us meet beforehand, they
wanted our first meet to be on camera,
filmed
and like everyone be quiet. There's 60
people on set and you guys can't say hi
to each other before. I'm like oh my
[__] god, give me a drink.
You know, but
I was doing this thing where I was like
I really want to see what I can do not
sober because I mean sober.
Not sober.
Because part of what I'm talking about
is doing hard [__] Mhm.
You know, and I think I was able to
curate my life where I didn't have to do
anything hard.
Everything was pretty easy because I
said so, because it could be. You know
what I mean?
And so I was like nah, man. I got to
just [__] try to do it sober. And so
I did. And I was nervous as [__] the
whole time talking to him. I'm like oh
my [__] god, but like I'm looking at
him. I'm like
I've seen you in so many movies. You
look like an alien right now sitting
next to me. Is that how you feel right
now? Like what? It's like it's like it's
like when I met Snoop Dogg, which I was
very high and very drunk for.
But I remember looking at Snoop like
damn, like I just feel like you're not
even here right now, you know? But so I
did that with Will Smith and I was like
wow, man.
Yeah, like maybe if I was drunk would I
have like said something like way
funnier and cooler? Like maybe or I
would have like said something really
dumb.
But the worst thing about drinking your
way through things is that afterwards
for me I always end up giving the credit
to the alcohol and never to myself.
And so I robbed myself of so much credit
that maybe I deserved. Cuz I would get
drunk
and do the show or get drunk and meet
someone. And yeah, I crushed it of
course cuz I was drunk and I'm awesome
and I'm charismatic and da da da da da,
but then the next day I'm like
you're not that [__] cool, dog. You
had to drink to already do it like
and so
all last year I like really made it a
point to do [__] sober, hard [__] sober.
And uh
yeah, that's what I mean by the unknown,
man. It's like
I didn't know how that conversation was
going to
go sober.
And I just had to have faith. And faith
is a really tough thing for me to have
cuz faith requires me to trust somebody
that's not me.
And
in the past I'm not letting this [__]
out of my hands. I'm going to drink so
that I can make sure this goes well.
Cuz I don't have faith.
I'm not trusting anyone that is not me,
including God, the universe, whatever
you want to say. I'm not even leaving it
up to chance.
That's how like scared I was to
surrender and have faith.
It sounds like at this point now you're
like fully prepared to go into the wild
and like maybe you're you're not looking
back too much, it sounds like.
Oh, well, I mean, I look back in the
sense of
no, I definitely look back because it's
still easy to just like be comfortable.
Mhm. And it's But it's also like you
need to give yourself grace and give
yourself props for putting yourself in
those uncomfortable situations like that
thing or whatever. So For sure.
that's like it's a balance of like yes,
like do what you have to do, put
yourself into this unknown, but also
like if you're look looking back or if
you're nervous or if you're reverting
back to old habits, it's okay. Just
maybe have more awareness of that to
kind of keep pushing forward.
Yeah, giving grace is so important and
it's it's easy. I mean, you guys know
it's like if your life is set up in a
way where you can make it kind of easy
for yourself where like you don't have
to do hard things. Like I'm talking
about little [__] like dudes as adults
it's so hard to make friends. You know
what I mean? So it's like going up to
that dude at the gym be like you want to
hang out? Like
you know what I mean? It's like that
[__] that's hard and you can just
convince yourself like I don't got to do
that. Like my life is okay. It's easy.
You know, and so I think a lot of people
we stay where we're at because we're
scared to do the hard [__]
And so our life is a product of what it
looks like to just take the easy way out
with a lot of stuff. Yeah. Even like
going after your dreams and going after
that, it's hard, you know? It's hard to
have that oomph. It's hard to feel
motivated. It's hard all that stuff. So
that's really what this phase is about,
man. It's just
do the hard [__] and it's okay if you
don't know what it's going to look like,
you know? Do it anyway.
I think if you don't do the hard [__]
you just stay stagnant at that point.
For you as somebody who's so obsessed
with progress and like moving forward,
like how do you balance that like
driving yourself, but also that this new
version of yourself that's trying to
give yourself grace? Like where's the
balance? Where's the line?
It's so tough. It's such a good question
cuz it's so tough.
Uh, yeah.
Because I want progress so bad, but I
also know that nothing is linear. Mhm.
You know, there's going to be backslides
sometimes.
You know, I might go
you know.
I might say no to an opportunity cuz I'm
like yeah, I just
I'm I'm losing to myself this time. It
is what it is, you know? And I have
those moments and it sucks and it's very
hard for me to not beat myself up about
it
cuz I'm very quick to once again zoom in
on the problems and not acknowledge all
of the like strides I've made.
Mhm. And I think that's also
I think some of that is a
I just a lot of that might just be a guy
thing, too, you know? We're so
we're so used to knowing caring about
our accomplishments
that
when we [__] up
we don't say oh, look what we've done.
Like look what we've done and look how
far we've come. It's like
we're like nah, but we [__] up.
Mhm.
It's like focusing on the one negative
thing and not the 99 like amazing things
that you have done. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, that's an everyday struggle. Yeah.
I think it also depends on like what you
define progress as. I feel like I'm for
sure pre-Santiago or in the past like a
lot of that I'm sure was more of
external validation and external things
of like oh, I'm going to achieve this
material object or this material thing
that I know that I can have, but like
now it seems like there could be more
internal forms of progress. So what is
what is an
Can you give a definition of an internal
form of progress for you now that you're
striving for?
Healthy boundaries.
With what? Um
with my self.
So for example, like
I'm not going to talk to myself like
that anymore. Mhm.
You know. We're not doing that anymore.
Um
healthy boundaries
with
my family.
What I mean by that is
when people are going through a hard
time
I can be there to support, but I don't
have to emotionally get wrapped up in
your vortex. Mhm.
That's not I used to think that that
well, that's what love is.
You're in a hole, I'm I'm jumping down,
too. I'm jumping down into the hole.
Emotional boundaries, yeah, it's like
and that's really tough for me, you
know?
And so
that kind of stuff is is really what I'm
interested in nowadays because
that's real life to me, you know what
mean? Like that's my everyday life that
I deal with, that I've always been
dealing with. But I had my career to
distract me
from what was really going on with
myself or my family or
you know, ah [__] it, I'm going on tour.
You know, I don't got to worry about
this. I got an interview coming up like
whatever, I'll get around to it.
You know. 100%. Yeah. Um I didn't want
to ask a specific question about one
particular song. Um of course we don't
have time to like dive into every single
one, but I just picked one. Um
chew, so talking about moving in um
wild.
Yeah. Um which is the story about like
motivation and staying focused on your
goals and resilience and that kind of
stuff. Can you share a bit about how the
process has been for you shifting from
dark motivation to light motivation?
Ooh. Um And also what are you which one
are you referring to in that song, dark
or light?
Yeah, so dark motivation is when you're
operating out of this fear-based place
where
you know, it's you need you need to
prove people wrong and
um you're making an enemy out of your
goals and
it's just a very like
it's not a sustainable way
to operate, you know? It's not a
sustainable way to live and I know a lot
of people do the whole like well, it
worked for Michael Jordan. It's like
he's a basketball player.
And he did it while he was playing
basketball.
You know what I mean? Like we're people
living life. You don't need to like
you don't need to curate a problem with
someone just to give you an extra chip
on your shoulder so now you can be
motivated. That's not sustainable.
Um
and light motivation is just doing it
from love, you know, doing like
going after what I want because
I want to honor the gift of creativity
that I've been given. I want to honor
the gift of connection I've been given
with my fans. So I want to do something
with it. I want to honor that.
You know. Kobe talks a lot about like
you know being in the gym constantly,
that's that was honoring his gift.
He got blessed with the gift of
basketball and talent and all that [__]
And the way you honor that gift is by
going to the gym every day.
So for me
it used to be I'm going to the studio
every day
so I can [__] on everyone and let them
know I'm the [__] best. [__] y'all.
And all this dark energy. Now it's like
I'm going to the studio every day
because I have a [__] gift and I'm
going to honor it.
And I'll be damned if I sit and just
waste away. Like I got to honor this
[__] How was that shift for you? It's
[__] awesome because in the past I
thought, well, how am I going to conjure
the hunger I had when I was broke?
And I kept trying to pull from the same
well.
And you're going to get stagnant if you
keep trying to draw from that same well.
Because it's not real anymore. Like I
can't trick my brain into thinking that
I'm still trying to make it.
You know what I mean? But
I don't need to trick my brain. I can
just say
man, I'm [__] blessed to have this
talent, to have these fans, to have the
ability to express myself.
Um to have the clarity to express
myself. I'm going to the [__] studio.
I got so much to say. I got so much to
share.
You know. So in the song um moving then
which which one is it? Is it dark or
light? Moving is um moving is light
motivation, you know? Moving is
moving is
it's one of those songs where it's just
it's just something nice to hear as a
reminder
that no matter what, keep it pushing.
You know. And I think where I'm at in my
life now is I had to take a step back. I
had to cancel a tour. You know. And that
was like one of the hardest things I've
had to do because
um fear of letting people down has been
ruling my life forever.
You know, fear of letting my mom down,
my fans down.
The way my priorities have worked was
everyone else than me. Mhm. That's how
it's always been. So
moving is
moving is an important reminder to
myself that
I have to keep moving and even if that
means
and this is where I had to give myself
grace and this is where the unknown
comes in.
By canceling tour I was moving forward.
Mhm. Because I was moving forward
towards a life where I prioritized
myself for once.
I think I think sometimes selfishness
gets a bad rap. And I feel like
sometimes it's necessary. Like for me
like I
I think of the antidote to you know,
those kind of problems is like radical
self-love almost. Like you're supposed
to do that for yourself. Like calling
off tour, yeah, fans get upset, fans do
this, whatever, but like that's a
radical self-love for yourself. That's
something like it was really important
and necessary at that time. Yeah, so
important.
Um and I wanted to mention that like in
the past you I know that you talked
about um crediting a lot of your success
to having like positive delusions. This
is I'm thinking of like earlier you and
like uh it was all in your head, you
know, yellow covered book. Um and in
kind of explaining positive delusions
further, you know, believing that you
were going to get everything that you
wanted before you had it. Um whether
that be like plaques or money or like
whatever. Um is that having that type of
mindset something that you still stand
behind? And that you would recommend to
others starting off now trying to pursue
their passions?
Cuz it worked for you in the end. Yeah,
I think
you absolutely have to believe in
yourself. There's no way around it.
You know.
Um
we're all going through [__]
We all have things we're struggling
with.
The truth of the matter is there are
people that are less talented than you
who are going to get to where you want
to get to cuz they believe in
themselves.
So I do believe in positive thinking and
believing in yourself for sure. I just
know that that's not
the whole picture. Mhm. You know.
So it's the part not the whole. Yeah, I
think um
but to answer your question, yeah, you
need to believe in yourself. There's no
way around it. I've I've met a lot of
talented people
who just didn't think that they could do
it.
It's really sad and you can't believe in
other people for them.
You know. I had friends growing up who
were way better rappers than me.
Uh
way better beat makers, way more
musically inclined. They just didn't
think they were good enough.
They didn't believe in themselves.
You know. And
I think the antidote to use your word
for that is to once again honor the
gift. Recognize the gift. Like if I
could tell those people I was growing up
with who just gave up
if I could tell them something it would
just be
bro.
Maybe like okay, you don't believe in
yourself, you should believe in the
gift. The gift you can't deny.
You can sit down and
play guitar so [__] well and you've
never taken a lesson and you've been
playing for a month. Like
there are certain things that innately
some people can just do that are [__]
clear like you have a gift.
Believe in the gift and honor the gift.
And hone the craft and show up and and
and celebrate the gift. You know what I
mean?
Yeah.
And kind of
to add on to that, sticking with the
topic of like growth, going after your
passions, doing what you have to do. I
actually have a question that I wrote in
March of 2024 from a Discord stage that
you did. Um you mentioned that where is
it?
Um you were a proponent of the idea that
in order to achieve your goal,
especially as an artist, that you should
work harder than you're paid. Um as a
way of kind of showing your dedication
and discipline, strive um
um and that if you don't do that then
you just don't want it bad enough. Is
that something that you still believe in
and to what degree did that belief get
you to where you are today? Work harder
than what you get paid?
Yeah.
Um
that I mean that is why I got to where I
got. Do you still believe that that's
like a that's holding
back yourself? I we can just keep it on
artists, right? I think
you have to
put your head down. Not look up at the
scoreboard for a long time.
You know.
Like
make a bunch of songs, put a bunch of
songs out, keep it consistent and don't
check the scoreboard for years.
You know. There's so many people who
think they deserve something cuz well,
I've put 20 songs out. So?
Where is there written that if you put
20 songs out you get I just think people
don't keep it real with themselves about
what they're getting into. This is not
college. This is not if you go here four
years, you get handed this piece of
paper. That's a guarantee. That is not
this.
This is you can make a thousand songs
and have two fans.
There's no guarantee. So you're
inevitably going to have to work harder
than what you've actually got paid for.
That's
Get go ahead and get prepared for that.
With that, do you see any connection or
blurring of the lines of like that and
like hustle culture and like you know,
working yourself to the ground till you
have no nothing else left to say I hate
hustle culture so much. 24/7.
No days off.
Is there any connection with that
though, you think?
Um
no, cuz I don't believe in hustle
culture. Um I believe in sacrifice.
I believe in sacrifice and what I mean
by that is
it's hard to do everything.
You know. It's hard to go to the studio
consistently.
Um
work on your body consistently.
Make sure you're reading as many books
as you want to be reading, doing all
like Yeah, you have to make sacrifices,
you know?
I don't know if I would have made it if
I was trying to
have a perfectly balanced life
at the beginning.
No, I had to sit in the studio for
[__] months on end.
I had to sacrifice sometimes of not
seeing my sister or not seeing my family
or missing out on this or missing out on
that.
I believe in sacrifice.
Um
but I don't believe you have to
have zero balance in your life.
You know?
Is it possible to make it without any
sacrifice, you think? No. [__] no.
No.
No. No.
Um we're getting a bit into my like
random vault of questions from the other
ones, so they're unrelated but kind of
related. Um a long time ago I saw this
random video on TikTok of somebody who
was interviewing somebody else and um
the person was like a chef in a
restaurant and um they asked them um
what advice that that chef would give
any other professional or a professional
in their field and he responded,
"Anybody who is good at anything knows
they're not that good." I kind of wanted
to get your opinion on that.
Yeah, I think um
as as Let me frame it by saying this.
I have definitely become Yeah, you can
close that door. I've definitely become
my favorite artist, for sure.
Uh
with that being said
I go to the studio all the time because
I still think I haven't made my best
song yet.
You know what I mean?
And so There's always room for growth.
Yeah, and I think a lot of times
people maybe misunderstood
my messaging of like
I think I'm the best.
That was kind of the [__] I had to tell
myself
to keep me going when there wasn't any
proof that I was even good.
There was no fans. So, I was like,
"Well,
if I tell myself
If I tell myself something that reflects
my reality it would be that you suck.
So, I can't tell myself that. I'm going
to tell myself I'm the best and everyone
else can just [__] wait. You know,
but the truth is that
I always thought I needed to get better.
And I still think like that. Now, I
don't like to go too black and white
with it. I need to acknowledge what I've
done in the music I have made and the
great songs that have been written and
all that, but no, I think
I think to that chef's point, it's like,
"Yeah, everybody who's good at it knows
like
I wouldn't say you're not that good, but
kind of. Kind of. It's like, "Man, I
don't know. I still got to get way
better." And that speaks to like the
notion of humility, too. I feel like And
correct me if I'm wrong, I feel like
your opinion or your perception of
humility has changed a lot over the
years.
It has. How has it?
I used to say I hate the word humble and
I still like on a definition standpoint,
I do. I don't like it. But
humility, even though I know it's like
the same [__] word, but
I guess because I've reached this place
where I learned enough about myself
to
recognize that there's still so much
more I need to learn.
And so
I have the humility as I move forward in
my life to know that there's going to be
some things that don't go my way.
And that's just how life goes and it was
arrogant to think anything different.
You know? And by being humble in my
approach with life in the future and the
unknown, now if and when, not even if,
when some [__] up [__] happens in the
future, I'm not going to let it [__]
rank me
as if like, "How is this possible?
How are there problems?" You know what I
mean? It's like
there's going to be some [__] up [__]
and it's always going to be happening.
There's always going to be something to
be grateful for.
you know? Yeah, it's life. Yeah.
Um
So
again, with that but also kind of a bit
of a topic switch, but um music is a
tool that you've
used in the past and you currently to
express yourself creatively and clearly
many people are receptive and resonate
with your messages.
Um I'm curious that or I'm curious if um
would you say that you're a good
Hello, sorry.
Um would you say that you're a good
communicator to your family, your
partner, your friends and has music
helped with that in your communication
skills?
Jesus.
Uh
Um
I think I communicate better through
song as a cliche as that sounds.
Um
I think in person I tend to get
emotionally charged.
And so like
songs
allows me to like breathe.
You know? Songs is you're getting my
sort of like measured
response to what I'm dealing with.
In person a lot of times, you know, I've
gotten a lot better at it, but um
it's really hard for me to not spiral up
and get really agitated and annoyed with
a problem, with a mistake and
you know, it's caused a lot of uh
friction between me and my manager, to
be honest, but me and him just had a
really big breakthrough the other day
because the cycle that we would get in
is
you know, a mistake would get made and I
would approach him, you know, I'd call
him and I'd be like chewing his head
off.
You know, which doesn't put him in any
position to take accountability. It puts
him on the [__] defense. And so then
he doesn't take accountability. He goes
on the defense, which makes me even more
pissed off. So, then I'm start chewing
his head off again like, "The [__] bro?
Like, why did you uh uh uh"
You know? And then he gets more
defensive and it just goes around and
around and around and around.
And so
in a song, I can communicate what's
going on between us from a calm,
measured place, but in real time, in the
moment, I'm not that great. Yeah. I'm
communicating. No. I think that like it
makes sense and that's why they say that
music is a universal language. Like I
can I can't explain to you, you know,
how how love feels to me, but I can I
can play you Missing You Crazy. Or I I
can't explain like loss, but I can play
you Last Night. Like you know, there's
there's certain things that I feel like
music can explain better than words can,
even though there's words in music.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Um even in different
languages. Like you people resonate with
songs that are in different languages
for a reason. Um it's the vibrations
that you're feeling in your body and I
think that um it strikes an emotional
chord. Like psychologically in your
brain there's something that connects
you to music and I think that's like
beautiful cuz it also like in a way
connects us to you in a way. So, that's
just that's just really cool. Wow. Um
It's so true, though. Yeah.
Um
another question. Um so
Another random vault. Yeah, I think
these are my random ones. So,
um so over the past few years you've
dabbled in a lot of various forms of
creative outlets. So, not only are you a
singer, rapper, producer, but now you're
a published you've been a published
author
um and an actor. What are What first
What can't you do? And also what other
creative outlets
What other creative outlets do you plan
on exploring professionally? Personally,
I think you'd make a great comedian. I
think you have impeccable comedic
timing.
Thank you. Um can we expect a
motivational speaking tour? Like what
else what else do you have in store?
I've always flirted with the idea idea
to do stand-up. My brother does not
think I'm funny at all, but
but I think I'm funny. Anyway,
um thank you for saying that. Yeah. Uh
acting is something I'm really, really
into. Um
because it gives me community. And you
guys know a little bit about my music
making process. It's fairly insular.
It's very isolated and I'm lacking
community and that's why this album with
these two guys in the back was just so
[__] fun, man, because I got to just
make music with people and I haven't
like done that. Like I did it with
Santiago, but Santiago was really like
all producers and then I had Bibi
Bourelly there. He's an incredible
songwriter. So, we like did hooks
together.
But this was just more like
it was just more collaborative. It was
the next step in collaboration and it
allowed me to
feel a part of something with other
people
you know, on a day-to-day basis. Every
day we were making this [__] And um
yeah, so that's why acting for me, cuz I
made this movie in October. It's like
this
It's my first co-lead role. It's coming
out this October, like September,
October.
And it just opened my eyes to how
important community is and how desperate
I am for community and I think a lot of
us
really like everyone I've talked to or
maybe it's just everyone in my life like
start looking around being like, "Damn,
I don't really have that many friends at
all."
You know? And it's like
[__]
How do you make friends as an adult? Be
a stand-up comedian. Yeah.
But it's, you know, it's um
it's important to have people to share
your life with Mhm. outside of just your
partner.
You know?
It's important to just have people you
can share share stuff with. So. Yeah.
And like to that point, too, you're very
like well-known amongst us and like
everyone else on social media and
Discord and stuff for being so extremely
open and communicative with your fans.
Um and I again like I mentioned it's led
to so many amazing friendships and
relationships and people are married
from Discord. I don't know if you know
that, but people like
I knew yeah a couple How many people
just I know like I think two or three
couples from that. Yeah. So like again
that's just absolutely amazing and
insane.
Matchmaker. Yeah, for real for real.
Um and so you're also well known for
like having fan involvement. So on the
voting platform is for cities to tour to
you or songs to release and setlist
things like that.
Um and now you have a fan interviewing
you. So like again so much more
involvement and community. Um but would
you ever let a fan feature on one of
your songs or possibly collaborate with
like the production the beats. I wanted
to shout out Maddie from from Discord.
She's awesome with that like actually
fire.
Yeah, I would.
It was incredible and I loved it. I mean
I have done that before. So Mike Hardy
was a fan that was always sending me
beats on Twitter.
And one of them was really hard. So I
did it and we made the song called Old
Days. He was a fan. So yeah, it's like
to me greatness comes from all over. It
doesn't just come from like established
artists. There's so many incredible you
know like I said I found these two guys
on TikTok.
They didn't have a million followers.
How many followers did you have when I
called you?
2000.
2000? 2000.
Made the whole album with these guys.
You know what I mean? That's again like
what other artist does that like I just
like [__] that's fire. You know what I
mean? So if it's awesome I'm going to
[__] with it. Yeah, game game recognizes
game. So
Yeah, it's good. It's good. For sure.
Okay, so I have a couple few last
questions and for this
I wanted The reason why I'm here is
because of the Discord community. So I
wanted to include questions from them
from people that couldn't be here today.
Okay. And kind of give them a little bit
of a shout out.
Beautiful. So I think I have like three
or four. But um from Angel from Discord
she asks
you talk a lot about manifestation. What
is your dream or personal goal that you
haven't spoken about publicly yet
because it feels too vulnerable or too
big?
None. None. No.
No. And sometimes I feel like
This is when I start having an
existential crisis. So buckle up.
So
sometimes
Oh god. Well yeah, this one I haven't
shared with the world.
Sometimes I start feeling like what's
the point anymore?
You know like the opposite of what
you're talking about which is
I've done everything I wanted to do.
Mhm.
I really did. I
made a bunch of great music.
I've
impacted a [__] ton of people. I've
toured all over. I made it into arenas.
I've platinum albums. I've platinum
songs. I got my mom a beach house. I
bought everyone cars out with like
I did everything I wanted to do. And so
Do you feel Do you feel fulfilled?
No.
Um
And
I start getting in a real funky spot
mentally
because I'm like
Okay.
I'm going to make the album and then
tour it.
And then make another one and then tour
it.
Make another one and tour it.
Why?
Is that not what you like to do though?
It is, but sometimes I'm like but what's
the point? You know? Like sometimes I
feel like I'm tricking my brain into
thinking there's still more left to do.
And because I'm worried
that what does my life look like if I
actually say
I don't know. I think I'm done. You're
afraid to stop. Yeah.
Why?
Cuz I don't know what that looks like.
The end of No.
Interesting.
It's scary though because I start
getting to that place and it just
it just starts feeling Have you guys
heard of that like fisherman parable?
Where it's like
Yeah.
Man, I I'm probably going to butcher it,
but it's it's something like there's a
fisherman he's out on his boat small
boat. He's catching fish. Some American
business dude pulls up and he's like oh,
I want to invest in you. You're catching
a lot of fish.
And the guy's like what do I need that
for? So the guy's like well so I can get
you a bigger boat. The fisherman's like
and what? Well then you can catch more
fish. Then what? Then you can make money
and have a bunch of boats and have a
bunch of people catching you fish.
Then what?
Well then you can just fish whenever you
want.
And the fisherman's like isn't that what
I'm doing right now?
You know so That kind of like as you're
saying that it reminds me of like I
think you're speaking about earlier
today or like earlier in this interview,
but you know it's talking about like on
that journey of like trying to achieve
all your goals. Like when once you climb
that ladder once you get to the
destination like what are you left with?
And that's at the end of the day
yourself. So isn't that what this whole
thing is all about? Like isn't the point
just to like exist? Isn't the point just
to like
so, but I think
I guess there's no way
Hm. How do I articulate this?
Putting music out to me
I guess I still care more than I'd like
to admit about numbers.
Because putting out music to me
still feels like I need to play some
sort of game.
I still like I don't have it in me
to just say
who cares
about going number one. Who cares?
I'm ambitious. I like beating people.
You know what I mean? I like winning.
Feels good. Yeah, it does. And
I think part of me though desperately
desperately wants to just like make an
album
tell no one about it. Don't post
anything on social media and one day
just say album Friday. Post one link and
then get off social media again for six
months.
You know, but I'm like
Yeah, but that would probably like flop
week one and then you're like a loser
and then no one cares. You're such a
loser. Did I mention you're a [__]
loser if you do that?
You know, it's like oh man. All right,
well anyway I'm going to sign 18,000
vinyl.
I got okay. It's actually a perfect
segue into the next person's question.
Stitch from Discord. She wanted to ask
have you ever resented music or resented
like the the process? Cuz it sounds like
like yes it's your passion. Yes it's
what you've been doing for so long, but
if you keep asking yourself like all
right and then what and then what? Is it
still your passion at the end of the
day? That's deep.
Wow.
Have I ever resented music?
[__]
The thinker.
Um
Damn.
Maybe I have.
Do you now? No, I don't know.
Trying to think.
I think
not necessarily music. Sometimes I
resent becoming famous. Mhm.
So I resent my younger self.
Cuz I'm like damn bro.
It's a really stressful [__] life
constantly sweating.
So anxious.
All the time with this [__] There's so
much I have to deal with.
It's sick. I've seen a lot of places.
My mom's good. My family's good.
So that's cool.
But did it need to get this big?
Or did I Did it need to even happen?
Could I have just kept music as this
light airy hobby
that never had any
dirt thrown on it?
But you also mentioned in the past that
it's because of survival that you got
into it in the first place, wasn't it?
You had to.
Yeah, but that's me trying to be the
savior again.
That's me not trusting my family to
figure it out.
You know? And it's noble to say I got
it.
I'm going to save all of us.
You know? Like my old song Titanic.
You know?
But it wasn't my responsibility to do
that.
You know? You took it on anyways. My
parents didn't even put that on me. I
put it on myself. I took it upon myself
to be the hero.
Um
And so when you do that you rob people
of their competence.
It doesn't foster confidence. It fosters
mistrust.
Because if you keep swooping in and
saving people all that communicates to
them is you don't trust them. You don't
trust that they can figure it out.
And people are [__] resilient man.
Like a lot of people most people when
their backs are against the wall they're
not just going to [__] like curl up
in the fetal position.
They're going to go down swinging.
They're going to try something.
You know? But again when you're in that
survival mode like it's hard to trust
people. So like it's understandable, but
I get what you're saying.
definitely understandable, but I'm like
damn that you know.
Yeah, there's definitely real thoughts
about I haven't shared that one world
yet. I shared it with my therapist a
couple weeks ago and I'm like,
"Yeah, I don't know, man. Sometimes I
resent my younger self for doing all
this [__] you know, because
yeah, there's just times where
it's not fun anymore." Mhm.
Yeah. And like that makes me think like
for me personally, I remember growing up
like in school and stuff, people always
tried to say like try to find your
passion and make money from that. Like
that's what's going to make you feel
good. It's like finding a job that
doesn't feel like a job cuz it's doing
what you love. And then like in the
moment it made sense, but now thinking
about it, it's like for me it kind of
feels like we're feeding into that
capitalistic like everything has to be
about money. Why can't you just make
music to make music? Why can't you do
your passion, do what you love for the
sake of doing what you love and always
associating with money? I agree 100% and
I know like, you know,
I think that I contradict myself a lot,
you know, and I think that's natural,
you know, because
I agree with what you're saying in the
sense where it's like
maybe your passion should maybe your
passion should just stay your [__]
passion.
Mhm.
You know, as soon as your passion is
what is paying the bills,
the fun gets sucked out of it quick.
Mhm.
Cuz now you need it to to hit this
threshold numerically, monetarily. It's
got to do this or what, you know?
There's been more songs than I'd like to
admit that I have looked at
lesser than
because they didn't do something
numerically or monetarily.
And that comes from the pressure that's
on the music to pay the bills.
Like, no, you can't just be a little
[__] hidden gem. Mhm. You need to go
like this is me talking to my song. You
need to go out there and [__]
perform.
I need you to.
That's not [__] that's not what the
[__] this was supposed to be about.
Mhm.
But okay,
I'll just be like, "Yeah, it's fine.
It's okay." It's like that doesn't pay
the [__] bills.
So, to your point, yeah, I think
that's kind of I think where the
resentment comes from is
the music right now in my life has all
the pressure in the world on it to make
money, take care of my family.
So, it's like
you know, it's triggering for me when
people I hate using buzzwords.
Mhm.
It's triggering for me when fans say
like, "Oh, I wish you could make [__]
like your old stuff."
So do I.
Do you think that like maybe
life was simpler? Do you think Do you
think it's more stressful to create from
a place of no bills and no
responsibilities versus take care of an
entire family?
Mhm. Like which do you think is the
easier place to create from?
That's why back then I was able to make
songs about [__] driving around,
right?
That's how simple my life was.
Like, yeah.
That's how little problems I had in my
life. It was just
ride slow.
I'll be there at 3:00. Yeah.
So, maybe like what you need to do is
make a song for yourself now. Like
again, circling back to radical
self-love.
It's such a it's such a vicious loop I'm
in right now. Every once in a while I
have breakthroughs, you know, and I
think um
this is where the contradiction comes
in.
I think the music I make is awesome and
I love it and it's free and it's
liberating and the music on this album
is my favorite music I've ever made and
there's real creative
just
creatively free moments throughout the
whole project, but
I do miss when life was simpler. It's
easier to create. It just is, you know?
It's um
yeah, I mean I look back at all those
songs, Someone to Drink With.
Think about how simple of a song that
is. Mhm.
I just need someone to drink with.
That was the problem in my life.
So Was that I wanted somebody to share
this $10 bottle of fish eye wine from
Chevron.
Any takers? You know what I mean? Like
that was where I was at creatively. Like
in the studio like, "Man." Or like
Moonlight Atlanta. That was just me like
wow. There's the moon. The [__] moon
is.
So, does that mean that now when you
make music is are the numbers always on
your mind every single time? For sure.
And now it's like, "Fuck it. I love you,
boy." And it's like, "Holy fuck." Wow.
This [__] got deep. That's even more
pressure then cuz it's like like holding
both okay, I'm focused on the numbers,
but also like you're talking about deep
[__] talking about personal vulnerable
stuff.
Yeah. So, it's like
I'm sure like for you like equating
those numbers to like how important that
actually is or how good you were able to
represent yourself in that. Yeah. It's
tough cuz like I said, you know,
my life, my family's life relies on the
music doing well commercially, money
wise, straight up. There's no other way
to put it. Even now? Yeah.
You can't just make music and just write
and what, hope that like
it'll just work out?
Yeah. I could. That's scary.
That's just a free falling place. Mhm.
Um no, but I you know,
I'm not saying I make music from a place
of I'm only going to make [__] I think's
going to make money. If that was the
case, I wouldn't have [__] made
Santiago. Mhm. You know what I mean? I
wouldn't have done a deep therapy album.
I would just sit in the studio and try
to crank out as many Losing Controls as
possible,
you know?
Um
but I'm just highlighting the difficulty
in
creativity when you're younger and you
have less responsibilities. You're just
creating from a way purer place,
Mhm. you know? Rick Rubin talks about
keeping that childlike wonder in the
studio and and creating from that place.
Well, it's easy to keep it when you're
closer to being a child.
Mhm. And more naive. You know what I
mean? It's harder to do it when your
life's a little bit more complex. I had
this conversation with my therapist and
and she said something really
that I've always like carried with me,
which is
most people's lives are complex,
you know? And so
you just now need to figure out how to
deliver
the complexities in a simplistic way.
Mhm. And that's always my challenge. I
never want to go over people's heads,
you know?
So, on a song like I Love You, Boy,
like I'm going to call it I Love You,
Boy, you know, to try to make it clear
like there I Love You, Boy was never
said in that entire song. Mhm. The hook
is not even saying that. The hook is
saying I loved you more than I did
before. Mhm.
So, I'm like little things like that
where I'm trying to make it
I'm trying to make it easy enough to
digest while still delivering something
complex. Mhm. You know?
And authentic to yourself. Yeah. Yeah,
and it's it's tough because it's really
easy to deliver ride slow Mhm. or down
for you. I need a crazy [__] that's
down for me.
You know what I mean? But every once in
a while like,
you know, I don't know, man. Creativity
is weird. It's a weird like Mhm. thing
to sort of try to wrap your head around
because there's so many contradicting
moments
random moments like I've just noticed
that
when my brain turns off
and I get a visceral reaction in my body
and I feel possessed, that's when I make
my best [__] Mhm. That's 3:15.
That's Handsomer. And I know Handsomer
got like I feel like it got overplayed,
but Handsomer was bananas. When I first
dropped When I first played it, I knew
it was like out of here, you know?
Because it was I know how I feel in the
studio. Mhm.
I know that feeling of when it's like
this isn't even me doing this.
This is some other [__] going on.
I'm just like the vessel. Some [__] is
communicating with me
and I'm doing like cuz how did this
melody pop in my Where did that come
from?
Yeah. You can't touch it, you know what
I mean?
Um 3:15, going to a Turkish restaurant
with my girl and my mom and that sample
plays over the speakers.
What if we would have left 10 minutes
earlier?
Then 3:15 doesn't happen. Mhm. Um
so just moments where you really feel
like
God's presence, the universe.
Yeah, connected. Yeah, and what's so
tough for me as a creative and as
somebody who's ambitious
is constantly
searching for a miracle.
You know? Like that's what
essentially that's what chasing hits is.
Hits are miracles. You know how many
different things have to happen to catch
a big song like 3:15?
We had to first of all, I had to decide
to go to the Turkish restaurant to hear
this song that I would end up sampling.
We had to stay there for as long as we
did.
I had to come home, write what I wrote.
It had to come out at the right time
with culture and TikTok and whatever.
And somebody on TikTok had to post this
kind of video that make so many things
have to happen.
And
the appetite comes with the meal in this
life.
The more you get, the hungrier you get,
you know?
You won't be that hungry for a platinum
plaque
if you put out a thousand songs and
never even sniffed a thousand streams,
you know?
But like
because I know I'm capable of making
songs that reach a lot of people and
connect a lot of people, I'm like, why
can't I just do that every time?
Mhm. There's that pressure coming back
in. Yeah, it's like because I know I'm
capable of it. I guess the the closest
thing I could equate it to, but it's not
this because this is more in your
control in a sense.
But if you're an athlete and you just
scored 60 points in the game, you're
like, dog, if I can do that, why can't I
just [__] do it every time? Mhm. You
know? And so you might score 15 the next
game, which is objectively still an okay
game, but you're like,
nah, dog. Yeah. That's [__] I think
that's where you have to come to terms
with like you can you can only control
what you can control. Yeah, it's so
tough.
Yeah. It's so tough to detach from the
results when your life depends on the
results. Yeah. That's the conversation I
have with Boogz all the time is like,
man, when we were younger, just
living at our parents' house and we
didn't have bills and we're making songs
in the basement.
It's like we didn't care what the song
did
because our lives didn't depend on So
that kind of goes back to what you're
saying with like keeping the passion the
passion.
You know, and and some people have said,
I think Nipsey said this like
get something outside of the music
that's making money that can pay your
bills so that the music can go back to
being
and it's like
at first it sounded good and then I was
like
well, but then wouldn't that thing have
all the pressure on it? Mhm. Because
then
the music is sitting there in the wings
like, hey, you better [__] perform.
You like And so I guess my the answer to
that question is
there's no life that exists without
pressure. Mhm. And and like I said this
album and I know
sometimes I get embarrassed talking
about this [__] because I feel I've
always felt such a late bloomer
with like maturity
and like growing the [__] up
cuz I feel like I got money at 23 and
success and I lived in this suspended
la-la [__] land for years cuz I could
afford to.
And now I'm realizing like, damn, so
like bad stuff's always going to happen.
And like there's always going to be
pressure and pressure and it's like
yeah, I just could've swore that I would
I had so much more influence than that.
Yeah. I think that's not not something
to be embarrassed about though. I feel
like again like everyone goes through
that. Everyone everyone's understanding
of the fact that life is the way that it
is and
things happen at different periods of
our life from childhood, young
adulthood, adulthood like past that, you
know? So I think that
maybe that's another thing that you need
to give yourself some more grace for.
Definitely.
Yeah. For sure. Um I don't know how that
kind of
came across from the the second question
from the Discord member, but
I don't remember either.
I thought No, you're good. Um but uh so
another question from a Discord member
at Kim,
um who was at the other interview today,
but she says if you were to make a set
list for just yourself, so kind of
related to this, for just yourself and
not what you think the crowd or fans
would want, what songs would you choose?
I have my list, but I want to hear your
list first. Wow.
Yeah, we were talking about this off
camera how
it's funny that my set list is curated
um
in a way that aligns with my need for
validation.
And I had this conversation with my
therapist before the last tour.
And he said, have you ever heard of the
80/20 rule with set lists? And I said,
no.
And he said, 80% is for them, 20% is for
you.
And I was like, well, that's scary.
Because
I need to play songs that they like and
that they're going to sing along to.
Cuz if they're not singing along and
they're just looking at me perform, like
this sucks.
Like I'm doing a shitty job. It's a bad
show and like I just want everyone to
have so much fun every single [__]
song. So I will play whatever will give
you that. What would you choose though?
What would I choose as the set list for
just me not caring if people knew the
[__] songs?
Oh my god, it's hard to even like
separate myself from approval.
Um what do I like? Who am I?
to yourself right now.
Um
I think Bank Run
Titanic
Someone to Drink With
I Love You Boy
Um
Scared
Off to the Wolves
Voicemail
Begging You
Um
It's really tough
cuz I'm thinking about
what songs do I want to perform and I
can't help but keep thinking
well, I want to perform these songs that
they want.
Yeah.
You know? Wow, it's so hard to think of
what you want.
It's so hard to think about what I want.
Mhm. Because shows aren't about what I
what I want. Mhm.
To me, but I'm trying to get better at
that because it's tough. For my shows at
this point, there's fans who have been
there seven times. This is their seventh
time seeing me. And so then I feel bad
when I'm like, god damn, dog.
You sure you want to come?
Cuz it's going to be a lot of the same
songs. Um
But I'm like
there's also so many fans who hit me up
every tour like, it's my first time
seeing you.
And what do I look like not playing
Losing Control? Mhm. You imagine? Like
I'm looking at myself like as a fan of
me. I go to Russia, you don't play
[__] Losing Control?
I'm riding. You know what I
the 80/20 rule kind of makes sense then.
It's like the majority of it should be
like your your hard hits, but like for
people that have been to seven or 10 of
your shows, I'm sure they will have even
more appreciation for like the lesser
played songs. It's like, wow, this is
such an amazing experience to hear this
song that you rarely ever sing. So I
think even that could be more like
impactful. Yeah, and I think, you know,
I took a step in that direction last
tour and it was good and I'm going to do
it again this tour. Like I'm going to do
the hits because of those reasons I just
said, like somebody's first show and I'm
not going to do what they want. Yeah.
Like I'm not going to do do it myself.
But with that being said, it's like, all
right, so I might play 20 to 23
25 of those like the hits that we all
know.
But then I'm going to do
the songs off the new album that I want
to do. Mhm. Like I'm going to do this
song I have on the new album called
Trying. That's so [__] hard. Mhm. And
I don't give a [__] how many streams it
does. I'm doing it.
As you should. Oh, thank you. I'm going
to do
one of the songs that I want to perform
off the album. The song called Forever.
Mhm. That is just [__]
to me
it's like
I've always said I didn't ever really
make love songs. I made relationship
problem songs. Mhm. Which is real. I
didn't have love in my life in that
department. Now I have love in my life
in that department, but there's still
problems. And so this song Forever to me
is like Mhm. one of the best
relationship problem songs I've ever
made. So I'm going to do Trying cuz I'm
going to Now I'm going to give you the
set list from the Okay.
Write this down, guys.
I'm going to do Trying. I'm going to do
Forever.
I'm going to do
um
a song called
I'm going to try to do this song called
Right Now.
But that [__] hook is
bonkers high.
So I'll probably like
I probably won't sing the hook.
Um but it's such a good song. I want to
do a song called Cyclone
off the new album.
I'm going to do song called Go Up, which
is just this like
disgustingly hard rap song.
It's like turn chopping your head off
[__] raps. Also, for all the Chop
fans, uh
the album starts off vicious.
First song is just barring out. Second
song is Dumb. I love that. Um
Then what else? Trying, Forever, Right
Now, Cyclone
Go Up
Crazy, obviously. Crazy such a smash.
Move In.
May Oh, Penthouse
That's eight.
And then I'll probably throw in some
like um
cuz that might be it off the album. I
got to look again. But then I'll throw
in some like just throwbacks. This is
where I'm going to allow y'all to vote.
Because like I don't y'all don't need to
vote on like, should Losing Control make
the set list?
You know what I mean?
But I want to like throw up songs like
Titanic, Someone to Drink With, We Just
Haven't Met Yet. Um
Moonlight in Atlanta. You know what I
mean? Like
those songs that were like on SoundCloud
that are kind of slept on Yeah.
Because personally, I want to do Someone
to Drink With. So actually I'm doing it
anyway. So that one won't be on the
voting campaign.
Yeah, I want I wanted to share my list
too. I have Bank Run, Bank Run, 3 AM,
Voicemail, Status, and Lake Como.
Status? That's my favorite song. Like me
and my brother and I rap it like in the
car all the time, so The flows on that
are insane. It's so hard. Yeah, thank
you. You're welcome.
really? Yeah, I like that one. Wow.
Yeah. Thank you.
See, Lake Como is one of those songs I
thought it was awesome. It came out, it
didn't do [__] Now I'm like, meh. And
that's a problem, you know? Me and Boogz
have this conversation all the time,
man. It's like we can't as artists, we
can't allow the numbers to make us feel
less about our songs. Like that's [__]
up. Mhm. Oh, you only like your song
after it comes out if it got 100 million
streams? That's such conditional love
with your own music,
you know?
And again, too, like for for example, if
you were to sing that like on tour, like
for me as somebody who knows that song,
loves that song, like that would be such
a cool experience for me, and I'm sure
so many other people. So, that's even
more of an incentive, like play those
sleepers. Like even if it's not the
whole, you know, arena that knows it,
there's going to be some, and I think
that that's going to mean a lot to them.
Well, here's the dilemma. We were
talking about this off camera, too.
As much as I wanted to do some songs for
me at the shows, there is also a truth
to a performance that
you do too many songs that people don't
know, and I've done it before, the
energy gets sucked out of the room.
And then it's an uphill battle the rest
of the night trying to get that back to
that place. It's like, for example, if I
did
What They Want, Do Myself, Pull the
Trigger, Psycho Part Two, Losing
Control, Goodbye,
boom, right? It's [__] turn,
everyone's going crazy. And then the
next five is like [__] That, All Sue,
Status,
uh
I Love You, Boy,
uh Money on Me,
it's like
To play devil's advocate, though,
to play devil's advocate, though, like
yes, that the energy gets sucked out,
but that's from your perspective from
the stage. You don't necessarily know
what the fans are feeling in in the, you
know, in the audience.
Cuz you know everything. Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Um all right, so what
so right. Well, you know what it is?
It's um
it's once again,
if I play a song that everybody's
singing along to, they're not looking at
me. I'm no longer being perceived.
They're distracted.
And so now I can be more comfortable
here.
Or I can drink, but I'm not going to do
that, right?
Uh anymore. Yeah, but if I do a song
that nobody knows,
well, now they're all really looking at
me cuz they don't have anything
distracting them.
And now it's like, what are y'all
looking at?
You know, turn around. That's true. I
think, yeah, there's there's points to
be made on both sides, so I I perform
with my back.
It's like performance art.
No, I promise you there's
a way to do
It's part of the album.
Um another question from Rachel from
Discord. Um your immersive experiences
for the Santiago listening party meant
so much to your fans. I was also at the
also at the Atlanta one, and that was so
sick for me to experience. Um do you
think that you'll ever create another
moment like that, and is that something
that we could see with a wild?
Where's Jerry at? Jerry would love this
one. We're trying.
They cost so much money.
Uh that Santiago, all those cost me $4
million.
Of my own money.
And for reference, Santiago did not make
anything close to that.
I It's I lost so much money on Santiago,
you know? And I still love it.
Uh
They cost a lot of money. That's the
dilemma.
And once again, it's tough for me to
This is like when This is the con of
wearing so many different hats.
It's tough for my business brain, cuz as
an independent artist, I'm the label,
right? I'm my own label.
It's tough for me as a business hat on
to say,
you spent $4 million,
that album made 300 grand. Maybe you
don't need to do that again.
You know? And so like we're trying to
pull this crazy [__] off for Wild,
it's coming in at an outrageous number.
At first, to do one thing, they were
talking about 1.5. I'm like, you're on
meth, it's not happening.
But we're trying to like spend a back
and forth. Wow. Um
So, I'm trying, but my business hat
comes on and is like,
hey, [__] remember we did this last
time?
It didn't do anything. Yeah. It didn't
It didn't make sense. Yeah. And so it's
tough for me to like once again, just
like I don't know, it's all good. Yeah,
that that makes a lot of sense. Yeah,
but I I hate that it comes down to that,
but it's like
damn, bro.
You can only do so much. I can do it,
it's just like my business manager gave
me some of the best piece of advice
ever.
He said, once you get and I don't know
if this only applies to once you get
rich. He said, once you get rich, it's
no longer can I afford this, it's should
I?
And that's been tough for me, cuz I'm
like, if I can, I should.
I feel that. And like to that point,
too, I do want to also just say like the
fact of you doing those Santiago
experiences is so like, again, now
hearing the economic
cost of all that, it really changed like
it's it's cool to get the behind the
scenes of that, but like as a fan going
to those events, like that is that
experience is something I will never
ever forget. Like I
[__] ever. I shared like a hotel room
with like 10 other Discord people. We
were just like all together and like all
came together from
On the floor. I have videos. Like under
the chair, under the desk.
Two to a bed, two to a bed.
that from like elementary school,
sleeping for a [__] tornado. Just
like doing that, and
people
Holy [__]
And like coming to your event, yeah,
honestly, like and just like going to
that
[__] you know what I mean? And I think
Not to interrupt you, cuz it's but
I'm so proud that we did those events.
I think
it was really really special, and I
think there's a big part of me that
wants to always do [__] like that for
every album, but I'm like, look, I got a
lot of money, but if I keep doing that,
I won't. And like I got to take care of
my whole family and like holy [__] I
can't keep spending $4 million on albums
that make 400, you know? It's like And
the reason I wanted to bring it up is
just again, just to share like and
express
like from a from a fan to you, like the
appreciation, the gratitude for that.
And like I for one recognize like you
didn't have to do that. You could have
just like released the album, we
listened to it, like that's the done
deal, but like the extent that you went
to, three different experiences, all so
unique in their own ways, and like like
getting to meet you, getting to ask you
questions, like that's again, no other
artist does [__] like that, you know
what I mean? So, that's again why I feel
like your community, your fandom is so
like special and strong in a way that
like again, like I listen to a lot of
other artists that like sure, yeah, like
they I can ask them questions on their
Instagram lives, they know who I am,
whatever, but not does not even come
close to the way that you like share
your life with your fans, and that you
allow them into your life. So, truly
from the bottom of my heart, like I
really do appreciate that, and we don't
take that for granted.
I wanted to say that. That's beautiful.
Thank you. Yeah, for sure. No, and I
want to do like I want to do sick [__]
with this album just because
it's also just about expressing myself.
You know, sometimes you can only say so
much in the music, and like
you know, and I you know,
like I said, that whole can I afford it,
should I afford it. I like doing nutty
[__] cuz it's awesome.
You can do cost-effective nutty [__]
too. We support that.
It would be a sick I'm sure there's ways
to do it. And then I'm doing like the
comparison thing, like [__] man, like
I went so above and beyond for Santiago.
How do I compete with that? Like
I can't just do some whatever [__] It's
got to be like something.
or yeah. It's got to be crazy. It can't
just be like, yo,
I don't know. It's going to be sick, so
it's um
But yeah, I wish, you know,
I wish it wasn't that,
you know, I wish it didn't just come
down to like
it's too much [__] money to just keep
doing it, but
But you know, that's the reality, and
like we're all
things I got to consider, you know? It's
like I don't get investments from
people, like I fund all my [__] you
know? Pay for all of it, like I paid
800 grand up front for 80,000 vinyl, you
know? And we sold 20,000 of them,
something. So, it's like I'm losing
money, but it's like that is what
comes with this. It's like you want to
be your own label and like be an
independent artist, you're putting the
money up. Yeah. You know? So,
it's um
yeah, it's just things that I a bunch of
[__] I got to juggle, you know?
I think
you know, to get like real practical,
one of the things I'm very proud of is
that I have been able to maintain my
money and not blow it, you know? I look
at my house sometimes, and I'm like,
damn, man,
I've lived here
longer than we lived in any house
growing up.
Like that's a sense of pride for me,
like I'm proud that I can
I can still be in this house, Yeah. you
know? And so
I think there's a real fear of losing it
all. There's a real fear of making that
one bad money move that all of a sudden
like
his momentum and then like streams go
down, and then oh my god, you thought
you were going to get like that forever.
You know, it's like those are real
thoughts, so like I get real paranoid
with with [__] like that. And I've
always been like that with money. It's
not necessarily cheap, because
I spent a ton of money on
ridiculous [__] but um
it's just
when it's you and you alone, you know,
taking care of people, you can't just be
on some whatever [__] You got to look
at everything
two, three, four, five times. That makes
sense. Like you you had no other choice
but to do that, or else like you would
lose all your money, so
Exactly. Exactly.
sense. And again, we as fans do
understand that, so you don't have to do
crazy events
every time you drop an album, you don't
have to have every single event, but we
do appreciate it.
Thank you. Of course. All right, so my
last question is honestly a lot of the
fans wanting updates for certain things
that you mentioned you're going to do.
So, I'm going to go by one by one.
The first one, when is T-Pain coming on
Spotify or dropping on Spotify?
Oh,
um [__]
We could do that whenever. Can you
backdate it though? Do you know you can
make it
so that it's not like my most recent
release, it's just on Spotify? Just so
it doesn't pop up as it Is that even
possible?
Yeah, we'll look into it. I just keep
forgetting. Yeah, that's why I'm
reminding you. Here we go.
And that went like viral on Tik Tok or
it is going viral the past couple of
seeing it now, too. Like it popped back
again.
isn't out, they just think it's T-Pain's
song. It So, I'm like ah
That's so funny. That [__] was funny.
And similarly, can you put Inside on
Spotify?
Inside? Oh, that's SoundCloud. Yeah.
Staying inside, not going out. I like
that one. I like that one. I forgot
about that one.
Remind me.
Maybe. Yeah. Okay.
What else you got? Um Palermo.
When's that dropping? Palermo.
Um
Palermo should be
September-ish.
Here's why it ended up getting delayed.
The [__] I use in my hair is red. But
then I was like, "Well, wait a second.
Doesn't it make sense
to make stuff for all hair types? Isn't
that the natural I look at it like my
music, right? It's like
I didn't do I didn't make a song, drop a
song, make a song, drop a song when I
was doing a song a week. I had 26
in the stash so I could be consistent.
And I know what's going to happen. I'm
going to put out
my curly hair shampoo and people are
going to be like, "When are you making
something for straight hair?"
And I'm just going to be like, "Fuck, I
should have thought of that."
Sounds like you're wanting to people
please everybody.
Um so, now it's like, "Okay, I'll get
the curly hair ready.
And then wavy and straight and
I don't know." Fine, maybe it'll be
[__] next year.
All right, so to be determined.
Um
next thing um you mentioned you wanted
to do a podcast. Um kind of similar
about that.
Or nor. I just feel like
I'm going to get canceled like episode
one.
You won't. I just There's no shot that
if I That doesn't mean that I'm going to
say some foul [__]
It just means that like
I'm just going to be rambling. Isn't
that what you're doing on Discord
anyways? Yes.
be recorded and put on YouTube. Yes.
So, what? Do it.
I feel like it would be a little bit
more unhinged.
Because I would be So, I have a room in
my house that's like set up for podcast.
And like I don't need anyone there to do
it. So, it'd just be me in a room in my
house, ultra comfy.
Just talking.
I think that sounds amazing.
Now that I say it out loud, I think once
again the fear of it is just
But if I do the podcast, I'm going to
get bigger and more people are going to
be looking at me and then you know, it's
just that damn man.
That same It's like that same cycle.
There you go. That same uh
I was going to do this artwork for this
album cuz I kept having this visual
where it was me
floating up like a balloon cuz I kept
seeing this over and over in my head. Me
floating up like a balloon and I'm like
so happy. I'm just like floating up. And
then this like
disgruntled like
angry, resentful me keeps jumping up and
grabbing my [__] foot back down.
Where do you think you're going? You
know what I mean?
And that's how it constantly feels.
Like, "Oh, that is a good idea. Wow,
that would be fun."
Oh.
Now, where are you going?
You know?
Yeah, I got to get through that. It also
just sounds like you're overthinking it,
too. Maybe a little bit. I would not
kidding.
Yeah.
That's Okay, so maybe to be determined
for that, too. Maybe. Yes.
God damn it, I'm tired of myself. We
aren't. Yeah, well, okay. All right, so
speaking of yourself, the last one is um
you mentioned I don't I think it was
last year or two years ago that you
wanted to make a movie about yourself.
Like write it yourself, star in it.
Could that still be something that we
see
something that is like actually very big
priority right now. So, the script is
written, we have a producer on board.
Wow. Um
Yeah, we're doing that. That one is for
sure happening. Wow. Uh do you have a
time frame?
No, because So, the way it works or how
it's been explained to me
um
you get a script, which we have.
You get a producer, which we have.
The producer then goes and sort of
assembles the Avengers, right? He goes
and gets a good director. He goes and
gets like one other
actress who's like popping, right? And
so now you have a producer, a script, a
director, me who can like sell tickets
to the movie theater, and another like
popping actress who can like sell
tickets. And you take that package and
you go to
the studios
or you go to like Netflix, Hulu, and you
pitch it to all of them and you say,
"Anyone in?"
And you hope that one of them says,
"Yeah,
I'll buy it for X amount of money." And
then they pay for the development of it.
Or
you get the package and you fund it
yourself.
So,
you can imagine which route I'm probably
going to end up taking.
So, that's once again it's like that's
another thing where it's like, "How is
this that?"
So, maybe don't do the
wild events.
Yeah, I don't know. It's you know,
whatever. We're going to figure it out,
but that movie is for sure happening.
I'm so amped about it.
Cuz I got this one coming out this year
and
um
Yeah, I'm really I'm really excited
about that one. That one is for sure I
just did the meeting 4 days ago. 5 days
ago about it. So, very real thing. Yeah.
You mentioned I think that you would
consider having fans as extras.
Yes.
Is that something that you can still do?
why not? Cool. Yeah, depends on where we
shoot.
Yeah, the extras in that, the fans in
that city. Cool. So, good to know for
us.
I don't think they like shoot anything
in LA like that. Cuz the taxes out here
like, "No, it's just so expensive to
shoot."
So, they shoot everything in like, you
know,
Toronto or [__]
you know, they're not shooting [__] in
New York. They're shooting it in
Toronto. That's why Yeah, that makes
sense. Yeah. All right, well, that was
all my questions. So, thank you again so
much.
make some noise for Zena. That was so
good. Thank you.
And um
I just want to, you know, say thank you
to everyone who came tonight. I know
it's late. I'm [__] exhausted.
And uh I think I'm just mainly
spiritually tired of myself. And
emotionally tired of myself.
Uh but I do want to thank all y'all for
coming and um just being along for this
ride, you know?
I know that everyone has their own [__]
going on, you know? And
I don't ever want to come off like
feel sorry for me, and none of that.
That's not at all what the MO is. The MO
is I just want to express what I'm going
through in hopes that it creates another
point of connection for us and I can
make some [__] good songs from it and
you guys enjoy it and it does something
for you. You know? Um and I also want to
say
for anyone coming to any of the shows,
I appreciate you because I know it's
[__] a [__] economy.
And
to spend whatever money you have on
concert tickets
almost seems unwise.
You know what I mean?
Wow, thank you so much. So, it's like
it's it's not lost on me how artists are
having a hard time selling tickets, you
know? It's not
it's not what it used to be. There used
to be less artists touring cuz there was
just naturally less artists out.
And so there wasn't so much competition
and the economy wasn't as [__] So,
for people to still be buying tickets to
come see me, especially when it's like,
"Bro, I've seen you six times." It's
like dog.
I don't even know why you came twice.
Like, I'm super like I get if you
wouldn't even even come once on me.
You know what I mean? Like, cuz I can't
even do that. I used to think like that.
Real fans will go to the show. Not true.
Not true.
Some fans don't have disposable income.
And they're bigger fans than people at
the [__] show.
I'm a massive fan of artists I've never
seen live. I have no desire to see live.
Cuz I just don't like shows.
That's also like quite the conundrum.
Very interesting. Given the depression
that you're in.
concerts.
So, that I think that's also why I like
I'm like, "I can't believe you would
come see me." Cuz it's not an activity I
would do. I think everyone sounds like
[__]
I hate when they do different renditions
of the song.
Like
like where they change the melody.
You know? Don't change the melody.
Like, imagine if I started to sing
Losing Control and I just start changing
the melody of Losing
It was a hit for a reason, dog.
Sing the [__] we know. I don't know, now
I'm going off on my like band because
I've gone to shows and I'm like
bro.
Get the [__] out of the show.
quickly, too, I don't know if I've
actually ever told you this, but the
first show of yours I went to,
um I was in grad school
the melody.
No, no. I was in grad school in Vermont
and
um you had a show in uh yeah. You know,
you had a show in Montreal. So, I drove
2 hours across the border by myself just
to see you like perform, then came back
home that same night. So, like that's
the
What Montreal show was that? 2022?
No, no, couldn't have been. Um 2021, I
think.
Okay.
Laval.
Oh, yeah.
Laval, yeah.
It was an amazing show. Like I have like
a video
I have a video reaction of me like
exiting the venue just talking to myself
in my phone like that was the sickest
[__] ever. Yeah, that was a crazy show.
But
see like I rely so much on the fans
energy. It's very hard for me to have
fun on stage if the fans are like not
crazy and that's something I got to work
on.
You know, I envy artists who can just
like
you're just up there having a ball even
though like
they're not.
You know what I mean? Like
how?
I could do it when I used to like just
get hammered on stage. Like that's easy
but
That's hilarious. Um
you know and I feel bad for certain
cities cuz there's cities that
I wouldn't go to again
because
the fans just
weren't engaged in the way I wanted them
to be but it's like you know but maybe
that's how they enjoy shows.
Maybe that's how they thought It's not
good enough for me. Yeah. This kind of
fan or else like it's so bad.
But Montreal was crazy
like I remember leaving that being like
that was genuinely I think till this day
actually the would be best concert I've
ever been to. Mind you I've seen J Cole
live front row. I've seen a lot of so
many like amazing artists like front row
and I think to this day that show in
particular is the best one I've ever
been to. That means a lot. One of my
biggest fears is scrolling on my Tik Tok
and seeing a video that says I went to
Russ's concert and it was awful. No.
That's one of my biggest fears. Whenever
I see whenever I scroll on Tik Tok
and a video like a concert footage of
mine comes up I immediately scroll past.
Oh my god there was one from like
like
Gulf Shores show like in Alabama. Wait,
you saw it?
Oh I don't even want to [__] know
then.
Um but I was like I this has a lot of
likes.
I'm scrolling. I don't know what this is
cuz it's just like
Ah. Yeah. But I I crossed the border for
you so. Thank you. And back the same
night so. I think also I just try really
I do try really hard so it sucks when
[__] doesn't when people don't like it.
I try really hard man.
Yeah. That was a good show. I'm going to
go look at that video now.
Was it good or bad what they were
saying?
Bad? Oh.
Oh god.
I got to slow blink. Oh my god I'm going
to spiral tonight. I'm scrolling on my
[__] bed so sad. Let's not do that.
Oh they said it was a great show. Was it
the pants I was wearing? Was it that
video?
Yes. Oh I saw that video.
That was awkward.
Yeah. Jesus Christ. But yeah I think
That's a good video. That I constitute
that as a good thing. It's a good video.
But yeah anyway sorry I'm [__]
completely rambling. But yeah I say that
to say
I appreciate everyone who comes to a
show
cuz I know you don't have to. I know you
have a million better things to spend
money on and
it means a lot and just listening to my
music means a lot. Give my new music a
chance.
There's a line on my new album. Sorry
I'll wrap it up.
There's a line on my new album
where I say
um
how long will they be open to I say how
long will they be open to receive my
message I'm 32 now. Um
yeah how long will they be open to
receive my message I'm 32 now. If you
were in the genre that I'm in you would
be too now.
And what I mean by that is it's not lost
on me that it is hard to maintain
care
from fans as a musician as you get
older.
People naturally don't care as much like
and I always get real freaked out. I'm
like what if this is the last song
people care about?
Because you don't know when it is and
what I mean by that is
if you go to a Bon Jovi show or Bruce
Springsteen
those fans don't give a flying [__] what
he just put out. They're like play your
[__] from '77.
You know what I mean? Like that's the
reality.
And it's like I don't know what his last
new song was where people were like and
I'm out.
I'm done. And I don't know what it's
going to be for me and I don't know how
I will be able to function if I really
know people don't care about what I'm
doing anymore.
You know? And so
that also makes me really hyper vigilant
and not able to give myself any time off
cuz I'm like dog people care still. I
should take full advantage. I have to
give them every single song that I've
ever made in my entire life while
they're still looking at me and still
caring.
You know what I mean? Those are like
real thoughts I have cuz I'm like what
if the next album
it's like
and it's just Yeah. I hear that fear but
also like if you were to stop making
music tomorrow the legacy that you'd
have is still incredible. And like I
know that you're not going to do that
but
I don't know
how to exist without making music and
sharing.
I've spent at this point
I've almost spent
I've spent more years of my life making
music
than I have.
I started making music at 14. I'm 32.
I've been making music for 18 years.
I don't even know what that [__] looks
like.
To be like oh it's all good like I had a
good run.
I don't know. What am I going to do with
my [__] time? Yeah. You know? How do
I find my place in the world if I don't
find it through music and connecting
with fans so.
Yeah.
That's scary. Like asking yourself what
are you outside of music? Oh boy. Yeah.
You want me to [__] spiral then
that's that.
I don't think we have the time for that
but Yeah. That's a whole that's 2 hours
more.
Um
yeah I don't know. I think that's why
I've had to
build out my life
work on becoming a better son, better
brother, better friend better partner
all that because you're right it can't
just be
you're just an artist. It's got to be
more than that. Yeah. So I appreciate
everyone coming out. I will stop
rambling. Make some noise for Zedd one
more time. Thank you Zedd. Thank you.
Incredible.